SHEREEF ELPRINCE

340 East 23rd Street, New York, New York 10010 (917) 667-5855 - selprince@avarisadvisory.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Results-driven senior executive with 20+ years of progressive experience in the Emerging and Frontier markets private equity and investment management space with extensive contacts throughout the Middle East. Possess a combination of investment acumen, private equity skills, execution track record and turnaround experience.

SKILLS

- Negotiation
- Cash flow management
- Investment banking
- Private Equity
- Creative Thinker
- Real Estate

- Strategic planning
- Business development
- · Organizational turnaround
- Mergers & acquisitions

WORK HISTORY

1/2020 to Present

Managing Partner & Co-Founder

Avaris Real Estate Advisory – New York, NY

- Creating US products for Non-US investors with a strong focus on the Middle Eastern market
- Expanding Avaris' presence brand recognition into the US market with new engagement signed

03/2017 to 12/2019

Co-Chief Executive Officer

Auerbach Grayson – New York, NY

- Reporting to the board of Auerbach Grayson
- Leading a firm of over 50 employees through a transformation from a traditional equities broker into a global financial services platform with a focus on delivering services through technology in Emerging and Frontier markets
- Drove implementation of new market expansion to propel business forward and adapt to market changes. Led company to the highest monthly revenues and profitability in over 10 years
- Renegotiated loss-making contracts into profitable contracts which reduced operating expenses of the firm by 30% within a year
- Grew the topline of the core business by over 20% to US\$ 22 million

 Bolstered Equity Capital Markets revenues for the company by 20-fold through a proactive approach with our global partners

07/2016 to 02/2017

Head Of Alternative Investments

Beltone Financial Holding - New York, NY & Cairo, Egypt

- Identified and appraised investment opportunities for Beltone Holdings through an opportunistic approach throughout Egypt and Africa. Typically looking at deal sizes between US\$25-50 million
- Established a real estate fund supported by innovative products to bridge the financing gap real estate players were facing in Egypt
- Established a sports fund that would develop talents in Egyptian athletes with the aim of elevating Egypt's Olympic ranking and competitiveness
- Oversaw Auerbach Grayson post acquisition and its transition into the Beltone Group

10/2015 to 07/2016

Group Chief Financial Officer

Marakez For Real Estate Investment - Cairo, Egypt

- The Groups entertainment assets occupy 9.5 million ft² (Al Hokair Group) making them one of the Middle East's most dominant players
- Core committee member that oversaw all of the firm's investment decisions, expansion plans, and plan funding
- Led the turnaround of the Group's finance operations in Egypt, which restored financial credibility through a rescheduling of payments to better match operating cashflows and eventually restructured the existing loan facility (US\$ 240 million)
- Reduced operating expenses by approximately 50% in one year through the introduction and implementation of policies and procedures
- Created alternative funding strategies in a high interest rate environment to help propel the company's aggressive expansion strategy

12/2012 to 10/2015

Managing Partner & Co-Founder

Avaris Real Estate Advisory - Cairo, Egypt

- Established a real estate advisory firm offering strategic and financial advisory services, investment opportunities and funding options to real estate investors and real estate developers in Egypt
- Created innovative real estate products that offered solutions to the financial crunch and high interest rate environment in Egypt. One such product created a hedge for real estate developers against a devaluing currency while offering investors an opportunity to make over 50% return on their investment

- Advised client on their overall strategic and financial plan (including budgeting, planning and management reports) and land bank use (approximately 107 million ft²)
- Advised flagship client on their successful launch of their project Almaza Bay in a turbulent marco environment (over US\$ 125 million worth of sales in Phase I)
- Advisory work included the master planning, product placement, marketing and sales strategy, sales training and financial planning and modeling - June 2014

04/2006 to 11/2012

Managing Director

Qalaa Holdings, (previously know as Citadel Capital) - Cairo, Egypt

- Sat on the board of the firms' US\$1.2 billion investment into upstream oil and gas and oversaw all operations
- Led a team of professionals on the acquisition of TSX listed Rally Energy upstream oil and gas company (recognized as the largest LBO in August 2007) - Citadel Capitals' first cross border acquisition (US\$ 1 billion) - August 2007
- Raised approximately US\$ 400 million in equity for the transaction
- Creatively generated US\$ 150 million to assist in deleveraging the company and injecting fresh capital into the business
- Arranged for approximately US\$ 600 million in locally and internationally sourced debt - including a senior, mezzanine, murabaha, hedge and convertible loan
- Carried the upstream investments through the turbulent market and in particular, negotiated with the international and local Senior and Mezzanine lenders on a restructuring cure
- Managed the staffing of Citadel Capital's professionals on all transactions

EDUCATION

2019 - 2020

Columbia University, New York

Fintech Bootcamp - A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, SQL, Big Data, Ethereum, Blockchain, and Machine Learning.

1997

BA: Economics, Cairo

American University

Cum Laude

.....

INTERESTS & SKILLS

Hobbies/Interests:

I enjoy swimming, yoga and mountain climbing.

Other Information:

Nationality: US Citizen

Date of Birth: June 22 1975